Every night a different nightmare.
Until Dawn is a horror, mystery film directed by David F. Sandberg.
One year after her sister Melanie mysteriously disappeared, Clover and her friends
head into the remote valley where she vanished in search of answers.
Exploring an abandoned visitor center, they find themselves stalked by a masked killer and horrifically
murdered one by one...only to wake up and find themselves back at the beginning of the same evening.
Clover Paul, played by Ella Rubin.
Max, played by Michael Cimino.
Abe, played by Belmont Cameli.
Melanie Paul, played by Maia Mitchell.
Dr. Alan Hill, played by Peter Stormare.
Nina Riley, played by Odessa A'zion.
Until Dawn is a 2025 American survival horror film adapted from the 2015 video game by PlayStation Studios, and it is set
in the same universe while featuring an original standalone story that expands upon the game's mythology.
The film was directed by David F.
Sandberg, and written by Gary Dauberman and Blair Butler.
It stars Ella Rubin, Michael Cimino, Odessa A'zion, Ji-young Yoo, and Belmont Cameli as a group of friends who end up in a secluded area embedded with a time loop
mechanic; a threat is out to hunt them where dying restarts the night with a new threat each time, and the only solution is to survive until morning.
Peter Stormare also stars, reprising his role from the game.
In January 2024, Sony Pictures announced the film's development with
Screen Gems and PlayStation Productions set to produce.
Casting announcements were made throughout 2024 and principal photography
took place between August and October 2024 in Budapest.
The crew features frequent collaborators of Sandberg, including composer Benjamin
Wallfisch, cinematographer Maxime Alexandre, and editor Michel Aller.
Until Dawn was released in the United States by Sony
Pictures Releasing on April 25, 2025.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $54 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of witch, haunting,
abandoned house, survival, memory loss.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.